JARRETÉ BARNETT

jarretebarnett@gmail.com



(860) 614-9019



South Windsor, CT 06074

SKILLS

- CSS *****
- HTML *****
- SQL *****
- Git ★★★★★
- Java ★★★★
- JavaScript ★★★★
- jQuery ★★★★
- Node.JS ★★★★
- React ★★★★
- Angular ★★★★
- Python ★★★★
- TypeScript ★★★★
- Amazon Web Services ★★★★
- MongoDB ★★★
- Agile Scrum ★★★

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut

Storrs, CT • 07/2021

Certification: Full Stack Software Engineering

Central Connecticut State University

New Britain, CT

No Degree: Liberal Arts And General Studies

Howell Cheney Technical High School

Manchester, CT

High School Diploma

CERTIFICATIONS

- UConn Coding Bootcamp
- AWS Cloud Practitioner
- Woz-U Application Development & Java Intensive Program

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An experienced Full Stack Software Engineer with background in building and maintaining server database applications, as well as client-side rendering for intuitive and responsive operating systems. Proven analytical and problem-solving abilities, supported by intensive training and verifiable certifications in software engineering and server-side computer sciences. Versatile working habits suited for either team-oriented or remote work conditions. Proficient in diligent scrum facilitation, sprint planning, and backlogging. Established track record for pursuing new challenges, including those involving opportunities to learn new technologies, languages, coding libraries and frameworks.

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- · jarretebarnett.github.io
- linkedin.com/in/jarretebarnett
- twitter.com/jarretedotio

WORK HISTORY

Turnberry Solutions - Associate Software Engineer

05/2022 - Current

- Team is tasked with the responsibility of developing and refining Pay with Rewards features which offers users redemption rewards for eligible purchases.
- Make daily collaborative effort with product managers to designate top priority stories that can be managed and completed within current or upcoming sprints and iterations.
- Manage company repositories to modify applications and files as needed in order to optimize
 configuration and functionality, as well as eliminate any conflicting or obsolete code.
- Continual maintenance and validation of code changes and database configurations with the primary purpose of refining and securing REST APIs which handle critical customer data.
- Periodically facilitated scrum sessions to discuss best practices with team members when necessary, and committed to regular sprint elaborations to exercise due diligence on recently created or backlogged design stories.

William Raveis Real Estate Inc. - Licensed Real Estate Sales Associate 02/2020 - Current

- Manage a personal CRM database of customers and clients.
- Marketing for social media-centric engagement, reaching hundreds of active users monthly.
- Prospecting inventory for seller interest, market data, and inquiring customers planning to buy or rent.

The Coder School - Instructional Coach

11/2021 - 04/2022

- Provide support to students who are learning new software frameworks and languages.
- Relay notes of progress to both parents and internal administration.
- Refine students' skills in languages such as Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, etc.

Keller Williams Realty - Licensed Real Estate Sales Associate

07/2019 - 01/2020

- Consultative experience with sellers inquiring about the marketability of their homes relative to
 existing inventory and proximity.
- Managed client expectations proceeding closings, as well as the technical diligence required to research relevant property data for customers.
- Closed over \$200,000 of volume within the first three months of licensure.
- Effectively closed home purchases expediently in a six-week timeframe.